Okay, so let's do the backward pass now
using the one method.
Alright, so here with the
forward pass, we already
did the forward pass on
the previous video, right?
So we bring that forward to this one.
And the backward pass,
again, exactly the same as
before, we start at the end
and we work backwards.
Same principle, right,
the late finish of the
last activity is going
to equal the early finish.
Right, so for I, we're finishing on day
19.
so that's the early finish that is also
the late finish now how do we calculate
the late start before like the late start
before meaning in the zero method it was
simply late finish minus a duration except
this time now we have to remember to plus
one late finish minus the duration plus
the one so it's going to be 19 minus three
plus the one which is 17 right and again
it's on the critical path so bottom line
and top line are the same as it relates to
early start or rather as it relates to
starts and finish dates late start will
equal the early start late finish will
equal the early finish on anything on the
critical path so that again is the same
check and balance as before late finish
equals early finish late start equals
early start equals early start on anything
on the critical path okay all right now
let's think logically if i go all the way
across to a We are doing the one method,
right, we're doing the one method here.
If I, the last activity, if I has started
on day 17, that means the previous
activities, CF and H, should have finished
the day before.
Not on 17, but the day before.
So CF and H should have finished all on
day 16, or rather the latest they can
finish is on day 16 in order for I to
start on day 17.
So H then, the late finish of H will be
day 16.
H has to finish on 16 in order for I to
start the next day on day 17.
And then again, using the same math here,
right, it's going to be 16 minus the 7
plus the 1, so the late start is going to
be day 10.
And again, H is on the
critical path, bottom and
top are the same, right,
for the start and finishes.
how about f let's look at f again h the
latest h can start is on day 17 so the
latest f can finish is the day 16 f has to
finish on 16 so h can start on day 17
right and then 16 minus 6 plus the 1 which
is 11 day 11 and again f can start on day
10 or it could be delayed by one day and
start on day 11 no impact on the schedule
so f again has that float of 1,
which we'll fill out in the next video.
Let's look at C.
If you look at C, I is starting on day 17.
That means C must have finished the day
before, day 16.
And then 16 minus 7 plus the 1,
which is day 10.
And again, C can start on day 7,
or it could be delayed by three days and
start on day 10, no impact on the
schedule.
All right, now, let's look at E here.
again with f right f starts on day 11 h
starts on day 10 so again you have a
choice between 11 and 10 you take the
smallest number but then it's the day
before e has to finish the day before so e
has to finish then on day 9 so the h can
start on day 10 so again when they have it
whenever you have a choice you take the
smallest number right but then the late
finish will be the day before.
And then the same math again, 9 minus 2
plus the 1.
So the late start then is going to be 8.
And you can see again, bottom line, top
line are the same for the start and finish.
So if E has started on day 8, that means D
must have finished the day before,
day 7.
Then 7 minus 5, right?
So the late start, 7 minus 5 plus 1,
right, is going to be 3.
And again, it's on the critical path,
bottom and top of the same.
If you look at B, then, again,
same principle.
C and F are leading back into B.
C has a late start of 10.
F has a late start of 11.
You take the smallest number, but it's a
day before.
B will have finished the day before.
So instead of 10, it will have finished on
day 9.
And then for the late start, again,
the same formula.
Same calculation, remember to plus 1,
9 minus 4 plus the 1.
which is six.
If you look at G then, H, if H has started
on day 10, that means G must have finished
the day before, day nine, nine minus six
plus the one, right, which is four.
And the late finish of A, you have a
choice between B, D, D and G, right?
You have six, three and four late starts,
right?
B is the late start of six, D as a late
start of three, G as a late start of four.
You take the smallest number, but then
it's the day before.
A would have finished the day.
before.
So A has to finish on day two so that D
can start on day three.
And then two minus two plus the one,
which is one.
So you can see now that
even, especially now in
the backward path, it's
even more challenging.
The one method is a bit more
challenging because again, you
have to always remember when
to plus one and when to minus one.